# Victor L. Pagan

2307 Maedell Dr. Killeen. Texas

(254)458-8951

victor.pagan@live.com Personal Website:

http://victorlpagan.com

# IT Skills

Programming languages:

Proficient: Java, Adobe Flex

Sometimes: C++, C# .NET, JavaScript

· Web Technologies:

CSS, XML, Struts2 Adobe Flex, Servlets, JSF, GWT

· Java Technologies:

Java 4+, J2EE, Spring, Hibernate, JDBC, JMS, JavaMail, Swing, Web Services,

Software Engineering:

OOP / OOD, UML, Design Patterns, MVC, Test-Driven Development, Agile/ Iterative methods, Peritus Methodology

· Project Management:

Subversion software project, StartTeam

Development Tools:

Eclipse, IntelliJ, Netbeans, Maven, Ant, CVS,

· Servers/Databases:

Glassfish, Weblogic, JBoss, Tomcat, Jetty, Oracle, Postgres, MySQL, Apache

Operating Systems:

Debian GNU/Linux, Ubuntu, MacOS X, Windows XP

# **Professional Profile**

I am a Software Engineer and IT professional with a focus on Object Oriented Development and Design, preferably using Java and Open Source components.

My IT skills are based on 2+ years of hands-on programming experience and over 10 years in the IT field including formal education in Engineering and Computer Information Systems.

I developed and maintain applications for private individuals, overseas clients, government agencies and various small to medium-sized businesses.

# **Education and Studies**

**Temple College, Temple Texas** 

2012-2013 Continuing Education Units Java/J2EE on Weblogic 2012-2013 Continuing Education Units Agile Essentials

**Texas A&M Central Texas, Killeen Texas** 

2009-2011 Bachelor, Software Engineering & Database Design

**Central Texas College, Killeen Texas** 2009-2010 Associate, General Studies

Ponce Institute of Technology, Ponce Puerto Rico 1998-2001 Associate, Biomedical Engineering

Asuncion Rodriguez de Sala, Guayanilla Puerto Rico

1992-1995 High School Diploma, highest GPA of the school year

# Work experience

CGI, Belton, Texas

May 2012-present

# Consultant/Java Developer

- Designed and developed Java J2EE applications by setting expectations and features priorities throughout development life cycle; determining design methodologies and tool sets; completing programming using languages and software products; designing and conducting tests
- Recommended system solutions by comparing advantages and disadvantages of custom development and purchase alternatives
- Developed applications by coordinating requirements, schedules, and activities; contributing to team meetings, troubleshooting development and production problems across multiple environments and operating platforms
- Supported users by developing documentation and assistance tools
- Updated job knowledge by researching new internet/intranet technologies and software products; participating in educational opportunities; reading professional publications; maintaining personal networks; participating in professional organizations
- Enhanced organization reputation by accepting ownership for accomplishing new and different requests; exploring opportunities to add value to job accomplishments

#### **Central Texas College**

February 2012 - May 2012

#### IT Desktop Service Technician

- Maintained, repaired, documented, and upgraded computer hardware, software and peripherals within Central Texas College by adhering to documented standards
- Supported and maintained computer account policies following Microsoft standards
- Assisted Central Texas College staff with the installation, configuration and ongoing usability of desktop computers and laptops, peripheral equipment and software
- Worked with vendor support contacts to resolve technical problems with desktop computing equipment and software
- Ensured desktop computers interconnect seamlessly with diverse systems including associated validation systems, file servers, email servers, computer conferencing systems, printers, application servers and administrative systems
- Evaluated functional needs to determine specifications for purchases. Responsible for filling out, reviewing and completing tasks within the Service Desk ticketing queue
- Assisted deployment of mobile devices and troubleshoot problems

# **U.S Army**

May 2003 - May 2009

## Flight Operations Supervisor

- Served as the Flight Operations NCOIC of a deployed Aviation Squadron in support of Operation Iraqi
  Freedom; coordinated flights critical to the movement of personnel and equipment throughout Iraq and
  Kuwait. Installed and configured PC workstations, printers and database terminals
- Supported, installed and deployed LAN/WAN, Video Conferences equipment, and satellite
  communication devices as needed by the mission. Installed and maintained antennas, transceiver,
  and all types of computer and office equipment in a combat zone

# **Fresenious Medical Care Yauco**

August 2001 - May 2003

## **Equipment Technician**

- Repaired, installed, maintained, calibrated, and inspected complex medical equipment and other systems like network routers, desktop computers, printers and computer systems
- Instructed personnel in the safe use and preventive maintenance of all types of clinical equipment technologies and systems
- Served as temporary Chief Technician for a period of eight months. Maintain documentation on new equipment, inspections, and equipment repairs and failures
- Provided in-service educational programs on use of equipment. Evaluated emerging technologies and user requirements to identify more productive tools and applications in order to meet user needs
- Provided vendor comparisons and evaluations to choose the most cost effective technologies available to meet their needs. Suggested modifications to the standard as appropriate